A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Real Estate, Series L FA321
Rockefeller Archive Center
- New York Property
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Mortgages - City Investing Company, Correspondence, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 177)
    Purchased second mortgage on building.
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Statements, 1952-1954 (Box 25, Folder 178)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Minutes/Meetings, 1952-1954 (Box 25, Folder 179)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Audits, 1957-1960 (Box 25, Folder 180)
  - New York Property - Miscellaneous Legal Papers, Fifth Avenue Properties, 1957-1960 (Box 25, Folder 181)
  - New York Property - 2 Liberty Street, 76 William Street, 1943-1946 (Box 26, Folder 182)
    Property purchased in 1943, sold in 1943. Correspondents include V. Webb, A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - Sixth Avenue Properties - West 48th Street, 1943-1946 (Box 26, Folder 183)
    Management of property; possible sale. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman, Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - Sixth Avenue Properties - West 48th Street - Sale of # 1210-1216 to Evelyn Gauvin, 1944-1947 (Box 26, Folder 184)
    Sold to Evelyn Gawvin. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - Sixth Avenue Properties - West 48th Street - Sale of # 1221-1227 to Daron Realty Corporation, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 185)
    Property sold to Daron Realty Corporation. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - Sixth Avenue Properties - West 48th Street - Sale of # 1280-1286 Sixth Avenue (and 61-63 West 48th Street), 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 186)
    Sold to City Bank Farmers Trust. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 15 West 51st Street, 1938-1947 (Box 26, Folder 187)
    Property was purchased in 1938 to allow for future expansion of Rockefeller Center. Whittier Realty Company was formed to hold property. 1940, property was sold to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Rental arrangements; tenants; demotion of building. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - New York Property - 17-19 West 51st Street - General, 1934-1946 (Box 26, Folder 188)
  - New York Property - 17-19 West 51st Street - Purchase, 1934-1935 (Box 26, Folder 189)
  - New York Property - 17-19 West 51st Street - Conveyance to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1941 (Box 26, Folder 190)
  - New York Property - 21 West 51st Street, 1934-1946 (Box 26, Folder 191)
    Rental arrangements. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 23-25 West 51st Street, 1945-1948 (Box 26, Folder 192)
    Leased from Immer Realty. Corporation by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. through Haswin Corporation. Correspondents include B. Turnbull.
  - New York Property - West 51st and 52nd Streets - General, 1936-1947 (Box 26, Folder 193)
    Offers of property for sale in the area. Plans for developing area. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Phillip Keebler, Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 11 West 52nd Street, 1934-1945 (Box 27, Folder 194)
    Purchase by Portus Realty Company. Rental arrangements. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 14-16 West 52nd Street, 1945-1946 (Box 27, Folder 195)
    Purchase of property. Rental arrangements. Demolition. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 15 West 52nd Street, 1935-1946 (Box 27, Folder 196)
    Purchase. Rental arrangements. Demolition. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley, A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 18 West 52nd Street, 1944-1946 (Box 27, Folder 197)
    Purchase. Rental arrangements. Demolition. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull.
  - New York Property - 19 West 52nd Street, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 198)
    Purchase of property near Rockefeller Center. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 20 West 52nd Street, 1944-1946 (Box 27, Folder 199)
    Purchase. Demolition. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 22 West 52nd Street, 1935-1946 (Box 27, Folder 200)
    Purchase. Rental arrangements. Demolition. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Chipman, B. P. Turnbull.
  - New York Property - 24-26-28 West 52nd Street, 1943-1946 (Box 27, Folder 201)
    Purchase. Rental arrangements. Demolition. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, Phillip Keebler, A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 30-36 West 52nd Street, 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 202)
    Purchase of property. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 2-4 West 53rd Street, 1927-1945 (Box 27, Folder 203)
    Purchase of property. Management. Tenant relations. Buildings demolished to save taxes. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 6-10 West 53rd Street, 1932-1938 (Box 27, Folder 204)
    Purchased by Museum of Modern Art. Traded to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for property closer to Museum site. Buildings demolished. Land sold. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 9 West 53rd Street, 1911-1936 (Box 27, Folder 205)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased land from John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Land kept open to secure light for Alta Prentice's home at #7. Butted on Museum of Modern Art land. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 11 West 53rd Street - Museum of Modern Art - Alterations, 1931-1935 (Box 27, Folder 206)
    Rent of building to Museum. Preparing house for Museum use. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 11 West 53rd Street - Museum of Modern Art - Lease to Museum, 1931-1934 (Box 27, Folder 207)
    Rent of building to Museum. Museum leased house to save expenses. Might have folded at this time if house had not been made available. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 12 West 53rd Street, 1930-1945 (Box 27, Folder 208)
    Purchased in 1930. Sold in 1945. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 14 West 53rd Street, 1936-1945 (Box 27, Folder 209)
    Purchased as possible extension of Rockefeller Plaza. Sold in 1945. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 15 West 53rd Street, 1928-1938 (Box 27, Folder 210)
    Purchase of property. Management. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 16 West 53rd Street, 1927-1945 (Box 27, Folder 211)
  - New York Property - 17, 19 West 53rd Street, 1926-1940 (Box 27, Folder 212)
    Purchase, repairs, management. Turned over to Museum of Modern Art. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 18, 20 West 53rd Street, 1929-1938 (Box 28, Folder 213)
    Purchase. Management. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 22-24 West 53rd Street, 1928-1936 (Box 28, Folder 214)
    Purchase to block apartment house, protect 10 West 54th Street, and prepare for Rockefeller Center development. Management of property. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 26 West 53rd Street, 1937-1938 (Box 28, Folder 215)
    Not purchased. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 27 West 53rd Street, 1929-1946 (Box 28, Folder 216)
    Purchase; rental arrangements. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Chipman, B. P. Turnbull.
  - New York Property - 27 West 53rd Street - Sale to Wallace K. Harrison, 1946-1949 (Box 28, Folder 217)
    Payments on mortgage.
  - New York Property - 28, 30 West 53rd Street, 1928-1944 (Box 28, Folder 218)
    Purchase; demolition of buildings. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Charles O. Heydt, Frank S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 30 West 53rd Street, 1944-1953 (Box 28, Folder 219)
  - New York Property - West 53rd Street - Sale to Public Library - Purchase of 15 ft. of 15 West 53rd Street, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 220)
    Sale of land assembled along 53rd Street to Public Library, 1944. Strip of land sold to library. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - West 53rd Street - Sale to Public Library - Purchase of 26 West 53rd Street, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 221)
  - New York Property - West 53rd Street - Sale to Public Library - 24 West 53rd Street, 1948-1955 (Box 28, Folder 222)
  - New York Property - West 53rd Street - Sale to Public Library - Exchange of 18 West 53rd Street for 30 West 53rd Street, 1941-1946 (Box 28, Folder 223)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $275,000 twoard construction.
  - New York Property - (West) 53rd Street Parking, Inc., 1929-1934; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 224)
    Plan for parking lot; objections. Rockefeller Corporation finally got city permit to operate parking lot. Sale of land. Correspondents include F. S. Staley, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - (West) 53rd Street Parking, Inc., 1939-1959; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 225)
  - New York Property - (West) 53rd Street Parking, Inc. - Construction of Parking Lot, 1941-1945 (Box 29, Folder 226)
    Construction of parking lot.
  - New York Property - (West) 53rd Street Parking, Inc. - Lease, 1941-1945 (Box 29, Folder 227)
    Lease to parking lot corporation.
  - New York Property - West 53rd-55th Street - Deckins Corporation, 1935-1941 (Box 29, Folder 228)
    Corporation held 17-19 West 51st Street; was dissolved in 1941. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - West 53rd Street - C. T. Chambers Correspondence, 1932-1946 (Box 29, Folder 229)
    Correspondence of agent.
  - New York Property - West 53rd & 54th Street - Proposed Apartments, 1934-1938 (Box 29, Folder 230)
    Development to be built by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Studies made; plans never carried out. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, F. Staley, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - General, 1941-1957 (Box 29, Folder 231)
    Purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. for $190,000 in 1906; rented by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Remodeling. Rental after 1913; tenant trouble. After 1951 used by Nelson A. Rockefeller, International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC). Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. A. Staley, A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - Party Wall, J. B. Dickson, 1906 (Box 29, Folder 232)
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - Alterations and Repairs, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 233)
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - Transfer to Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 234)
    Gift to Nelson A. Rockefeller from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - Richard Cronan Lease, 1941-1947 (Box 29, Folder 235)
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - General Correspondence, 1905-1927; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 30, Folder 236)
  - New York Property - 13 West 54th Street - General Correspondence, 1928-1940; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 30, Folder 237)
  - New York Property - 14 West 54th Street, 1912-1921 (Box 30, Folder 238)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased property; repairs, rental; security measures for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s home at 10 West 54th. Demolition; lease arrangement. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 16 West 54th Street, 1912-1937 (Box 30, Folder 239)
    Purchase; repairs; rental. Demolition of building. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 16 West 54th Street - Duncan Chandler, 1912-1915 (Box 30, Folder 240)
    Architect advised John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on modification of 16 West 54th Street; supervised work.
  - New York Property - 17 West 54th Street, 1915-1936 (Box 30, Folder 241)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased property in 1916 to keep street residential; rented it to a doctor, who kept it until 1932. Building was demolished in 1935. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 18 West 54th Street, 1931-1937 (Box 30, Folder 242)
    Property purchased in 1935; was never rented. Building demolished in 1937. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 19 West 54th Street, 1912-1935 (Box 30, Folder 243)
    Purchased 1912. Rented as apartments. Tenant troubles. Demolished in 1935. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - New York Property - 20 West 54th Street, 1922-1934 (Box 30, Folder 244)
    Purchase, rental problems. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 21 West 54th Street, 1930-1939 (Box 30, Folder 245)
  - New York Property - 22 West 54th Street, 1914-1940 (Box 30, Folder 246)
  - New York Property - 23 West 54th Street, 1926-1935 (Box 31, Folder 247)
    Purchase, rental. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 24 West 54th Street, 1917-1936 (Box 31, Folder 248)
    Rental of house. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 24 West 54th Street - Dancer's Club, 1932-1934 (Box 31, Folder 249)
    Rented 24 West 54th to girls' club.
  - New York Property - 29 West 54th Street - Dancer's Club, 1927-1946 (Box 31, Folder 250)
    Purchase, rental, sale of property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 24 West 55th Street, 1935-1936 (Box 31, Folder 251)
    Purchase of property. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 26-36 West 55th Street - Spence School, 1927-1945 (Box 31, Folder 252)
    Property purchased from Spence School. Possible uses of building; demolition of building. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 104-106 Morningside Avenue, 1927-1937 (Box 31, Folder 253)
    Purchase. Rental by Lincoln School.
  - New York Property - 108 Morningside Avenue, 1933-1936 (Box 31, Folder 254)
    Purchased because was in vicinity of Lincoln School; demolition. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 406 Riverside Drive, 1956-1957; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 255)
    Purchase for future use of Riverside Church or Interchurch center. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. E. Siegesmund.
  - New York Property - 406 Riverside Drive, 1958-1961; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 256)
  - New York Property - 524 Riverside Drive, 1927-1938 (Box 31, Folder 257)
    Purchased to protect Riverside Church, International House. Neighbor threatened to sell to Negroes unless John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought property. 1935, given to International House. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 882 Sixth Avenue (now # 1252), 1929-1930 (Box 31, Folder 258)
    Purchased for Rockefeller Center Development. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 53rd-54th Street - Demolition of Houses, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 259)
    Real Estate Committee decides to demolish brownstone houses on 53rd and 54th Streets. Progress of work. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - New York Property - W. A. White & Sons Management Contracts, 1934-1938 (Box 32, Folder 260)
    Property management details. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - W. A. White & Sons Management Contracts - Properties, 1927-1928 (Box 32, Folder 261)
    Location of Rockefeller properties; tenants, rents.
  - New York Property - W. A. White & Sons Management Contracts - Arrangements with New York Consolidated Edison, 1920-1936 (Box 32, Folder 262)
    Group wholesale rates.
  - New York Property - West 123rd and 124th Street Properties, 1927-1936; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 263)
    Purchase of property to protect Lincoln School; change in population make-up. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, F. Staley, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - West 123rd and 124th Street Properties, 1937-1944; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 264)
  - New York Property - West 124th Street - Demolition, 1937-1938 (Box 32, Folder 265)
    Public protest; latters; clippings. Remission of taxes.
  - New York Property - West 124th Street - Miscellaneous Maps and Statements, 1934-1944 (Box 32, Folder 266)
  - New York Property - 400 West 124th Street, 1929-1941 (Box 32, Folder 267)
    Examination of title; recording of deed; employment problems. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, T. A. Porter.
  - New York Property - 402-404-406-408 West 124th Street, 1927-1930 (Box 32, Folder 268)
    Examination of title; payment of mortgages. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 405, 407 West 123rd Street, 1927-1936 (Box 32, Folder 269)
    Examination of title; purchase.
  - New York Property - 410 West 124th Street, 1927-1936 (Box 32, Folder 270)
    Contract provisions; payment of mortgage; examination of title. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 412 West 124th Street, 1929-1933 (Box 32, Folder 271)
    Examination of title; mortgage payment. Previous owner's problems. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Mary Fallon.
  - New York Property - 414 West 124th Street, 1927-1929 (Box 33, Folder 272)
    Mortgage payment. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 416 West 124th Street, 1931-1936 (Box 33, Folder 273)
    Purchase and details. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - 418 West 124th Street, 1926-1927 (Box 33, Folder 274)
    Examination of title; payment of mortgage. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 420 West 124th Street, 1926-1934 (Box 33, Folder 275)
    Review of contract, examination of title; mortgage payment. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Arthur Woods.
  - New York Property - 426-428 West 124th Street, 1927-1935 (Box 33, Folder 276)
    Examination of title; mortgage payments. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - 430-432 West 124th Street, 1927-1931 (Box 33, Folder 277)
    Examination of title; satisfaction of mortgage. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - West 123rd-124th Street - Lincoln School Lease, 1935-1946 (Box 33, Folder 278)
    Attempted sale to Teachers College; leased to college as playground. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, William F. Russell.
  - New York Property - West 123rd-124th Street - Proposed Sale, 1944-1948 (Box 33, Folder 279)
    Sold to New York City when city purchased Lincoln School from Columbia University. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - General - Real Estate Analyses, Statements, etc., Folder 1 of 2 (Box 33, Folder 280)
    Annual analysis of real estate for years 1932-1937 prepared for the Rockefeller Real Estate Committee.
  - New York Property - General - Real Estate Analyses, Statements, etc., Folder 2 of 2 (Box 33, Folder 281)
  - New York Property - General - Statements Regarding Rentals (Box 34, Folder 282)
  - New York Property - Clark T. Chambers, Inc. Report - 51st-53rd Streets (Box 34, Folder 283)
- Real Estate Committee
  - Real Estate Committee (49) - General, 1930-1938; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 284)
    Committee of Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt and Frank Staley to watch over John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s real estate investments; development of policy; sales, purchases. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frank Staley.
  - Real Estate Committee (49) - General, 1939-1944; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 285)
  - Real Estate Committee (49) - Letters of Appointment/Authorization, 1933-1944 (Box 34, Folder 286)
    To and by committee.
  - Real Estate Committee (49) - Reports, 1936-1947 (Box 34, Folder 287)
  - Real Estate Committee (49) - Minutes, 1932-1941 (Box 34, Folder 288)
- Haswin Corporation
  - Haswin Corporation - General, 1945-1951; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 289)
    Organized to purchase property on 51st and 52nd Streets; dissolved in 1961. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise, C. E. Siegesmund.
    212
  - Haswin Corporation - General, 1952-1958; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 290)
  - Haswin Corporation - Certification of Incorporation/Bylaws, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 291)
  - Haswin Corporation - Property Transfer to Rockefeller Center, Inc., 1946 (Box 35, Folder 292)
- Normandy Realty Company
  - Normandy Realty Company - General, 1930-1950 (Box 35, Folder 293)
    Organized to hold John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s property on 68th and 69th Streets between 2nd and 3rd Avenues. Property given to Memorial Hospital. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Frank Staley.
    224
  - Normandy Realty Company - Sale of Stock from Midtown to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1939 (Box 35, Folder 294)
- Sale of Property
  - Sale of Property, 3 Corporation to Mr. Rockefeller, 1940 (Box 35, Folder 295)
    Sale made to simplify John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s real estate matters. Midurban, Portus and Whittier Realty dissolved after sale; details of sale. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
    222
- Portus Realty Company
  - Portus Realty Company - General, 1934-1944 (Box 35, Folder 296)
    Purchased and managed real estate on West 51st Street. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
    223
  - Portus Realty Company - Treussier (Bretagne Corporation)/Bodenes, 1939-1945 (Box 35, Folder 297)
    Restaurant lease, 9 West 52nd Street.
- Midurban Realty Company
  - Midurban Realty Company, 1936-1945 (Box 35, Folder 298)
    Organized to hold 53rd Street property; 20 West 53rd, 3-5-7 West 53rd. Purchase and management of properties. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Frank Staley, Charles O. Heydt.
- St. Thomas Church Property
  - St. Thomas Church Property, 1907-1915 (Box 35, Folder 299)
    Neighbor relationship with St. Thomas Church; Rockefellers paint walls, watch over use of property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
- Seaboard Realty Corporation
  - Seaboard Realty Corporation, 1928-1932 (Box 36, Folder 300)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought real estate in Atlanta through Seaboard; land to be used for library to serve colleges for Negroes in Atlanta; General Education Board (GEB) reimbursed John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Corporation dissolved in 1931. Correspondents include Trevor Arnett, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    197
- Wilson Realty Company
  - Wilson Realty Company, 1905-1918; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 301)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. investment grew out of investment in Frasch Process Soda Company which owned land on Cleveland lake front. Management of land; filling in of lake. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gave stock to Foundation; repeated offers to sell tract failed. Correspondents include L. M. Bowers, Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Wilson Realty Company, 1919-1941; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 302)
- 17 West 54th Street Property
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Corporation - General, 1935-1939; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 303)
    Decision to build moderate-rental model apartments at 17 West 54th Street; for singles and couples rather than families. Nelson A. Rockefeller managed project; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a silent partner. Operation of apartment; management; sale in 1945. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Bryan A. Long, Frank Staley.
    225
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Corporation - General, 1939-1946; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 304)